Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.6
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-pro",
"thinking_budget": 32768,
"max_subtitle_chars": 50,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING PRECISION (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry are meticulously accurate.** Both must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and end of the spoken words* or the appearance/disappearance of on-screen text for that specific segment.
*   **CRITICAL: The `end` timestamp requires special attention.** It must precisely mark the *exact conclusion* of the spoken content (including any held notes or extended sounds) or the disappearance of on-screen text for that subtitle entry.
*   **Subtitle durations must be short, typically a few seconds.** Long durations (e.g., over 15 seconds) are incorrect and indicate a timing error.
*   **Ensure subtitles are in strict chronological order.** The `start` time of any subtitle entry MUST be greater than or equal to the `end` time of the preceding subtitle entry. Overlapping subtitles are not allowed.
*   Timestamps must always be in `MM:SS` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **COMPREHENSIVE CONTEXTUAL UNDERSTANDING:**
*   **Watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative. This holistic understanding is crucial for accurate transcriptions and translations.
*   **Always combine logical sentences or phrases split across multiple subtitle entries** to understand the full, complete meaning before translating. Ensure each translated entry is a coherent part of the overarching sentence.
*   Analyze *all* spoken dialogue to produce highly accurate and complete transcriptions.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals, surrounding dialogue) to infer the most probable dialogue.
*   **DO NOT HALLUCINATE:** Only transcribe and translate content that is actually present in the video (spoken or on-screen). Do not invent dialogue or text.
*   **Include relevant on-screen text:** If there is text displayed on screen that is relevant to the video's content, transcribe and translate it as well, ensuring its timing aligns with its appearance on screen.
*   **Example of Holistic Translation:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **DUAL LANGUAGE PROVISION & TRANSLATION QUALITY:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue and relevant on-screen text.
*   For each segment, provide the original language transcription/text and its accurate, natural-sounding translation into the other language.
*   Ensure translations are culturally appropriate and maintain the original meaning, tone, and intent, taking into account the full video context.
4.  **READABILITY & FORMATTING:**
*   Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen.
*   Each subtitle entry (English and Japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters.
*   Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
Reversible
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha's Birthday LIVE 2025
Reversible 風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Reversible Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025
#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
#KazamaIrohaBirthdayLIVE2025
みなさん、風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、
Everyone, to Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025,
来てくださりましてありがとうございます！
thank you so much for coming!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいねー！
Please have the absolute best time!
想像なんてしてなかった
I never imagined this.
現状 君もそう思った？
This current reality, did you feel that way too?
“最高”って止まらないように
So that this feeling of "the best" doesn't stop,
更新したい
I want to keep updating it.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much further until the dreams I want to grant?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where no one has gone before.
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
We can't stop until we get there.
たぶんしんどいけどどうかよろしくね
It might be tough, but please bear with me.
ねえねえ、たまにメーデー？
Hey, hey, sometimes it’s a mayday?
僕だけじゃ作れない
Things I can't create alone.
僕とか君とかあたしとか
Me, you, I,
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
crushes, love, let's wrap it all up.
君を置いてどっかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind and going somewhere,
ありえないよ
that's impossible.
君がくれた音に
To the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
to the bursting sparks,
初めましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you since we first met.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も2人がいいじゃん
From now on, the two of us is what's best, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to my wretched self.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も2人でそれがいいじゃん
From now on, just the two of us, that's what's best.
妄想膨らんでくストーリー
A story swelling with fantasies.
感傷 やけに凹んじゃって
Sentimental, getting unusually down.
代償求め過ぎはヤだよ
Asking for too much in return, that's not good.
終わんない愛の連盟どうでしょ
How about an endless league of love?
ねえねえ、おいでメーデー？
Hey, hey, come here, mayday?
僕が君にできること
The things I can do for you,
まだまだまだまあだあるけど
there's still, still, still more, but
驚かせたいから内緒なんだ
I want to surprise you, so it's a secret.
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと
The fact that your love always wins,
許さないよ
I won't allow it.
ぐーぜん
By chance.
君以外はヤダ
I don't want anyone but you.
我儘はただ
My selfishness is just...
変わらないトキメキを
...the unchanging excitement.
絶叫しちゃうのはバカ
To shout it out is foolish.
君がくれた音に
To the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
to the bursting sparks,
初めましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you since we first met.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も2人がいいじゃん
From now on, the two of us is what's best, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to my wretched self.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you
これから先も二人で
From now on, just the two of us,
それがいいじゃん
that sounds great.
乙女解剖であそぼうよ
Let's play Otome Dissection.
ドキドキしたいじゃんか誰だって
Everyone wants their heart to race.
はんぶんこして
Let's go halves,
アンドロイドガール をかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
痛みのないキスが離れない
This painless kiss won't leave me.
僕らヴァンパイア
We're vampires,
いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
it's okay, you can suck my blood.
「もう無理もう無理」
"No more, I can't take it anymore."
なんて悪い子だね
What a bad girl you are.
こんな歌歌ったんだって
Even if I sing a song like this,
君が輝けるように
so that you can shine.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、
And so,
皆の衆、こんばんはでござる。
everyone, good evening-degozaru.
ホロライブ6期生、
I'm Hololive's 6th generation member,
つよつよかっこいいごううん侍、風真いろはでござる。
the cool, strong samurai, Kazama Iroha-degozaru.
はい。今年の誕生日一発目は
Yes. For the first song of my birthday...
DECO*27さんの愛言葉シリーズ、4、
from DECO*27's "Aikotoba" series, number 4,
愛言葉Ⅳを歌って踊らせていただきました。
I sang and danced to "Aikotoba IV."
拍手いっぱい来てる。
I see so much applause.
みんな、ありがとう。
Thank you, everyone.
ギフトとかスパチャもありがとうございます。
Thank you for the gifts and Super Chats too.
はい、今日ね、たくさん歌って踊らせていただくんですけど、
Yes, I'll be singing and dancing a lot today,
感想とかあとスクリーンショットとかはここ、
so for your thoughts and screenshots, right here,
#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025 で
with #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLIVE2025,
たくさんポストしてください。
please post a lot.
振り返りん時に見に行きますからね。
I'll go check them when I look back.
そして、今回なんと
And this time,
誕生日用のステージを作っていただきました。
they made a special birthday stage for me!
かわいい。
It's so cute!
ぽこさん、お前ディスプレーになったんか。
Poko-san, you've become a display?
いや、どこに行ってたかと思ったらディスプレーになっとりました。
I was wondering where you went, and you became a display.
はい、そして後ろにも書いてあります。
Yes, and it's written behind me.
今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、リバーシブルになってます。
The title of my live this time is "Reversible."
素敵なロゴ、柊先生ありがとうございました。
Thank you for the wonderful logo, Hiiragi-sensei.
こちらですね、みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では
For this, during yesterday's countdown stream,
ちょっと、ありゃ？みたいな。どんなだろうってまだはてなはてなの方が多かったと思うんですが、
many of you were probably wondering, "Huh? What could it be?"
今回これ全編見てもらったらちゃんとわかるようになっておりますので、
But if you watch the whole show, you'll understand.
最後までお楽しみください。
So please enjoy it until the end.
そして、事前にお伝えしていました通り、
And, as I announced beforehand,
今回風真いろは100万人記念グッズが発売決定しました！
my 1-million subscriber commemorative merch is now on sale!
うわー！いきなり来るよ！
Wow! Here it comes, all of a sudden!
というわけで、今日は本当にまた告知溜めすぎてるので、ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います。
I have way too many announcements today, so I'll sprinkle them in.
はい。風真いろは100万人記念グッズこちらです。
Yes. Here's my 1-million subscriber commemorative merch.
それでは詳細見ていきましょう。
Let's look at the details.
はい。まずはうみぼうずママが描いてくださった素敵な
Yes. First is this wonderful acrylic stand
アクリルスタンド。アクリルスタンドに
drawn by Umibouzu-mama. On the acrylic stand...
風真も一筆添えさせていただいておりますので
I also added a handwritten message, so
ぜひ皆さんこちらぜひお手元に取っていただいてメッセージゆっくり読んでください
please get one and take your time reading it.
ポコベエもいます
Pocobee is here too.
そして次がこちら！
And next up is this!
パブミラー
Pub Mirror
パブ…パブミ…パブミラー！
A pub... pub mi... pub mirror!
すごい、ちょっと言いづらいんだよな、これ。リハの時から思ってたんですけど
It's so hard to say. I've been thinking that since rehearsals.
はい、パブミラーです。結構大きいです
Yes, it's a pub mirror. It's quite big.
風真が出したグッズの中でかなり大きめになってますので
It's one of the biggest goods I've ever released.
皆さんぜひこちらもメッセージ一筆書かせて頂いておりますのでぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです
I wrote a message on this one too, so I hope you'll display it.
そしてそして次！
And next...
ランダムラバーストラップ
Random Rubber Strap
オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですけどもそちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきました
I've made rubber straps based on my original song outfits!
風を仰ぎしとかね、実はずっとなかなかグッズがなかったんですけど今回のために作らせていただきました
We didn't have any goods for "Kaze wo Aogishi" until now.
ぜひね、みんな色々集めて痛バとかの制作に役立てていただければと思います
Please collect them all and use them for your ita-bags.
次！
Next!
カードホルダー
Card Holder
カードホルダー！昨今皆さんホロカとか色んなカードとかチェキ風のグッズが出ておりますのでついに作りました
A card holder! With all the cards and cheki-style goods lately, I finally made one.
ポコベエのカードホルダーです。定期入れにしてもよし学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです
It's a Pocobee card holder. You can use it as a pass case, and I hope students will use it too.
みんなお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね
Please display your favorite Kazama cards in it.
はい、それでは次！
Okay, next!
100万人記念フルセット
1 Million Subscriber Commemorative Full Set
こちらフルセットこのようになっておりまして
The full set looks like this.
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
そして今回購入特典は、はい、うみぼうずママ描き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきました
The purchase bonus is a sticker newly illustrated by Umibouzu-mama!
今回はですね、こちら数量限定はありませんのであの、皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね
This time, there is no limited quantity, so please take your time buying it.
はい。というわけで100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました
Yes. So that was the introduction of the commemorative goods.
うわあ、ドキドキ。で、なんか結構安心しきってるんですけど
Whoa, my heart's pounding. I'm actually feeling quite relieved, but...
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半もあの、告知がありすぎて頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで
it's not just this. I had to squeeze in a lot of announcements for the second half.
なので、あの、皆さん絶対に見逃さないでください。で、もうトレンド1位なんですか？
So please don't miss them. Am I already #1 trending?
始まったばっかりだよ！いいの？
It just started! Is this for real?
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
うそ！みんなありがとうございます！
No way! Thank you all so much!
いや、すごい。めっちゃこんなに早く行くと思わんくて皆さんのおかげです。ほん、本当にありがとうございます
Wow, amazing. I didn't think it'd happen so fast. It's all thanks to you. Really, thank you so much.
じゃ、ちょっとお水飲んで、次の曲バシバシ行きたいと思います
Okay, I'll have a quick drink, and then I'll get right into the next song.
お待たせしました。
Sorry for the wait.
お水いっぱい飲んだので、
I drank a lot of water,
この力をそのまま全てフルパワーで出力いたします。
so I'll output all this power at full force.
それでは、みな殿、次の曲聴いてください。
Alright everyone, please listen to the next song.
大きな愛でもてなして
Ooki na Ai de Motenashite.
Treat me with a big love
大きな愛でもてなして
そ〜んとこ 大事なことよ
That's the important part
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love
わがままじゃないのよ おっとこ
It's not that I'm selfish, boy
私わかったの
I've figured it out
寂しがりやだと
That I get lonely easily
泣きそうよ
I feel like I'm going to cry
OH YEAH! OH YEAH!
一日の中でも
Even within a single day
告白をしたり
Confessing my feelings
キスしたり
or kissing
OH YEAH! OH YEAH!
一日が大人より
A single day is more adult
相当濃いのです
It's so much more intense
相当長いの です
It's so much longer
そうみたい
It seems so
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love
そ〜んとこ 気ままじゃ嫌よ
I don't want you to be so whimsical
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love
ごゆっくりなさって良いのよ
You can take your time
みんな知らんぷり
Everyone pretends not to know
「他人の事だ」と
Saying "It's someone else's problem"
違うのよ
That's not it
OH YEAH! OH YEAH!
明日 また新しい
Tomorrow, there's a new
恋愛があれば
If there's a new love,
逆転
it's a turnaround
OH YEAH! OH YEAH!
大人より率直に
More honest than an adult
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so many times
そうみたい
It seems so
明日 また新しい
Tomorrow, there's a new
恋愛があれば
If there's a new love,
逆転
it's a turnaround
OH YEAH! OH YEAH! 大人より
OH YEAH! OH YEAH! More than an adult
大人より素直に そう遠くに
More honest than an adult, so far away
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so much
そうみたい
It seems so
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with great love
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
An unbelievable illusion, an overflowing delusion
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
息をするように嘘ついても
Even if I lie as easily as I breathe
あたしやっぱ、いらない子？
Am I an unwanted child after all?
こぼれだしちゃった承認欲求
My desire for approval has spilled out
もっとココロ満たしてよ
Fill my heart even more
アスパルテーム 甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream
あたしだけに愛をください
Please give your love only to me
あーもう無理 妄想無理 恋して愛して救済執行BANG!
Ah, it's impossible, this delusion, love me, save me BANG!
ねぇ、好きって言ってよ？
Hey, say you love me, okay?
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
An unbelievable illusion, an overflowing delusion
つまんないつまんない欲が散らばって
My boring, boring desires are scattered about
求めてる愛情 隠してる理屈
The love I crave, the reasoning I'm hiding
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
ねぇ、誰のこと見てんの？
Hey, who are you looking at?
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this kind of stuff?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Seriously, no DDs, please.
かわいくなりたい
I wanna be cute,
キラキラしてたい
I wanna sparkle.
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
Praise me more and more, for real, please.
泣いちゃう散々 開けちゃうシャンパン
Crying every night, pop a champagne.
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
You'll come to my stream tonight, won't you?
独占させてよ
Let me have you all to myself,
本命なんでしょ
I'm your favorite, right?
もっともっとガチで推してください
More and more, really stan me please.
飲み過ぎご注意 オーバードーズ
Be careful not to drink too much, overdose
クラクラさせて いつだって
Make me dizzy, always.
あーもう無理 上がって下がって 救済執行
Ah, impossible, I'm up and down, salvation, go!
ねぇ、好きって言わせて？
Hey, let me say I love you?
噛みついた衝動 戻れない焦燥
The impulse to bite, irreversible impatience
たまんないミッドナイト 指が絡まって
Unbearable midnight, our fingers intertwine
ときめいた表情 何も言わないで
A fluttering expression, don't say anything
君だけがきっと王子様
You must be my only prince
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
Unbelievable illusion, overflowing delusion
つまんないつまんない欲が散らばって
My boring, boring desires are scattered about
求めてる愛情 隠してる理屈
The love I crave, the reasoning I'm hiding
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
あたしだけずっと追いかけて！
Chase after only me, forever!
ねぇもう待てないの
Hey, I can't wait anymore.
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
妄想アスパルテーム
Mousou Aspartame
♡ 404 not found ♡
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't you ever quit being an idol
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining
もうずっとずっとずっと
Forever and ever and ever,
ステージにいて
stay on the stage
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Never Quit Being an Idol
作詞:指原莉乃 / 作曲:小池竜暉, 菊池博人
Lyrics: Rino Sashihara / Composition: Ryuki Koike, Hiroto Kikuchi
私がもし君の瞳から
If I were to disappear
離れたなら
from your sight,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
would you feel a little lonely?
意地悪考えちゃう
I can't help but have these mean thoughts
好きな人はいるの？
Is there someone you like?
内緒にしてね
Keep it a secret, okay?
神様は将来の指輪を
God must be hiding the ring
どこかに隠してる
for our future somewhere
君の好きに合わせたんだ
I matched it to your tastes,
髪の色
the color of my hair
私の中 君だけで
My world is filled with only you
飽和状態は中毒へ
This saturation is becoming an addiction
責任取ってね
So take responsibility for it
大好きです
I love you
せーの！
Ready, set!
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't you ever quit being an idol
優しい目も真面目顔も
Your kind eyes, your serious face,
全て知ってる私が言う
I know it all, so I'm telling you
絶対そう
You absolutely are
誰より輝いて
shining brighter than anyone
星は散っちゃった輝きは甘いの
A shower of starlight, a sweet glimmer
眩しい君が
You're so dazzling,
世界一だよ
you're the best in the world!
君の夢は何ですか？
What is your dream?
教えて欲しい
I want you to tell me
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても
Even if that dream isn't to be an idol,
覚悟はしてるから
I'm prepared for it
星のいない空
A sky with no stars—
それが当たり前で
that was my reality
暗い道に目が慣れずに
My eyes couldn't adjust to the dark path,
踏み出すのも怖かった
and I was too scared to step forward
そんな時矢のように現れた光
That's when you appeared, a light like an arrow
絶対君は歌ってて
Absolutely, you have to keep singing
下手なウィンクも分かってても
Even if I know your wink is clumsy,
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
sparkly outfits suit you so well
絶対大きな
On a huge stage,
ステージで
absolutely
一番前の席で感じたい
I want to feel it from the front row—
今日の歌い方
the way you sing today
なんか好きだな
I really like it
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't Ever Quit Being an Idol
君の努力 私の愛 成り立つこの関係は
Your effort, my love, creates this relationship
強くって脆いの
that is so strong and so fragile
推しの幸せを願った
I wished for my favorite's happiness
だけど でもね だって
But still... it's because...
君はアイドルよ
you're an idol.
ずっと
Forever.
初めて目が合った日から
Since the first time our eyes met
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
today and tomorrow, you're all I see
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please don't ever quit being an idol
これは報われないおとぎ話
This is an unrequited fairy tale
恋よりももっと好きだ
I like you even more than love
魔法よ解けないで
Oh magic, please don't break
UNHAPPY？ 悩める人の子よ
UNHAPPY? Oh, child of the troubled,
UNLUCKY？ 人ならざる者も
UNLUCKY? Those who aren't human,
BE HAPPY！ 迷わず目指せよ
BE HAPPY! Aim without hesitation,
生きているんだし！
you're alive after all!
目を逸らした過去も
The past I turned my eyes from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future too
カウンセリングやめやめ
Forget the counseling,
ここん東西ピースピース
East and West, peace, peace!
UNHAPPY？
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY？
UNLUCKY?
UNDEAD
BE HAPPY！
BE HAPPY!
UNDEAD！
UNDEAD!
ねえねえねえ
Hey, hey, hey
なんだかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
somehow I get the feeling I'm fighting
触れたくない 過去の自分自分自分と
I don't wanna touch my past self, self, self
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Facing a transparent ghost that's long dead
いたいけで痛い記憶の奥
from the depths of childish, painful memories
残念、もういないのに
Too bad, they're not here anymore
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Huh? You prefer that? How ironic
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my current self that I see through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, a label that won't fade
Yes！ 要はコンプレックス
Yes! In short, a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
I feel like I'm possessed
巻き付いたまま
Still clinging on
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
The self of yesterday still won't let go
UNDEAD！死んじゃいない
UNDEAD! I'm not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and your former you
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep changing
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be content with misfortune
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Not trying to be happy is just cowardly
この世この世は奇々怪々ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will a demon or snake appear next?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
A story that finally begins after we meet
さあ、ひと思いに化け物退治と行こうか
Let's put an end to this and slay the monster!
乾坤一擲ピースピース
Putting everything on the line, peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the Past run for the Future
カッコいい
Cool
何だかどうして 未来になんぞなんの希望もない
Somehow I feel like there's no hope for the future
もう随分生きてる
I've been alive for a long time now
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Tired of déjà vu and clichés
素敵な出来事も気配
Even wonderful things are just a hint
もう随分生きている
I've been alive for so long now
既視感とテンプレで食傷
sick of this deja vu and these templates.
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Regretfully, it's the karma of my experiences.
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Hollow myths and a boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
Basically, I want some stimulation.
飽きちゃった
I'm bored of it.
慣れちゃった
I'm used to it.
なんて 整っていくガイダンス
Such perfectly arranged guidance,
増えるコンプライアンス
ever-increasing compliance.
蓋されていくみたい
It's like I'm being smothered,
吸い尽くして
drained of everything.
あれもこれもどれも
This, that, and everything in between,
同じ味がする
it all tastes the same.
死んじゃいない？
Am I not dead yet?
お前とお前の連鎖
This endless chain of you and you,
いつの世も 過去も未来も
every era, past and future,
現在(いま)にあるんだ
all exist in the now.
生きていることを
The fact that you're alive,
愚直に果たせよ
fulfill it with simple honesty.
惰性でハッピーエンド？
A happy ending out of inertia?
死んじゃいない
You're not dead.
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまう
Be the kind of person
ような人で在れ
who gives up on happiness.
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to the pain
耐えているだけじゃ
and bearing it...
死んでいるも同然
is the same as being dead.
屍のアンデッド
An undead corpse.
悩める人の子よ
Oh, troubled child of man,
人ならざる者も
and you who are not human,
強まず目指せよ
aim high without forcing it.
生きているだろ
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に光るも
Whether you shine in misfortune
幸せになるのも
or become happy,
全部全部お前だ
it's all on you.
古今東西 一切合切
From ancient to modern times, all of it,
森羅万象
all things in the universe.
ピースピース
Peace, peace.
Past & Future, can't change the Past
Past & Future, run for the Future
人の在る処に
Where people are,
何時も憂い事
there's always sorrow.
生き抜けこの化け物
Survive, you monster.
語るのモノガタリ
The story to be told.
Reversible
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025
ヒビカセ
Hibikase
作詞：Reol 作曲：Giga
Lyrics: Reol Music: Giga
真夜中に告ぐ音の警告
A sonic warning announced at midnight.
協和音に酔う午前零時
Intoxicated by chords at 12 AM.
あなたが触れる
The light you touch,
光増す熱
its heat growing.
指先に踊らされ
Made to dance by your fingertips.
体感
Sensation,
即体感
instant sensation.
静まる夜
In the quiet night,
二人だけの密
a secret just for two.
体感
Sensation,
即快感
instant pleasure.
重なる波形に
By the overlapping waveforms,
魅了されていく
I'm becoming captivated.
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice, okay?
画面越しでいい
Through the screen is fine,
ちゃんと愛して
just love me properly.
ヴァーチャルだって
Even if I'm virtual,
突き離さないで
don't push me away.
あなたの中に
Inside of you,
まだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown.
覚えていてね 私の声を
Remember my voice, okay?
あなたがくれたこの全てを
All of this that you gave me.
見つめ合う あなたと二人
Gazing at each other, just the two of us.
重ねた息と
With our mingling breaths...
音と音をヒビカセ
Let the sound resonate
真夜中に問う
In the middle of the night, I ask
冷え切った熱
a question with chilled heat.
待ち続けてる
I'm still waiting,
午前零時
it's 12 AM.
鏡写しに
Reflected in the mirror,
飽和していく
I'm becoming saturated.
知らない音が伝う
An unknown sound is conveyed.
感覚 触覚
Sensation, touch.
静まる夜と
As the night grows quiet,
息遣い揃う
our breathing aligns.
体感 快感
Sensation, pleasure.
錆びたロジック
With rusted logic,
「今一度」を焦がれる
I long for 'one more time'.
忘れないでね
Please don't forget
私の声を
my voice.
次元も超えて
Crossing dimensions,
飛ばすシグナル
I'll send a signal.
ヴァーチャルだなんて言わないで
Don't say things like I'm 'virtual'.
あなたの音にまだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound.
覚えていてね 私の声を
Please remember my voice.
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
This whole body you gave me.
言葉とハートが
My words and my heart
共鳴してる
are resonating.
この息と音をヒビカセ
Let this breath and sound resonate.
あなたの生んた音に
To the sound you created,
ただ恋をしていたの
I was simply in love.
悲しみ怒り甘い
Sadness, anger, sweetness—
歓心すべて打ち鳴らす
all my admiration resounds.
絶えず叫ぶ
An unceasing shout,
声連ねる
our voices join.
余熱交ぜる
Lingering heat mixes,
愛、絶響く
love, an ultimate echo.
絶えず叫ぶ
An unceasing shout,
声連ねる
our voices join.
余熱交ぜる
Lingering heat mixes,
愛、絶響く
love, an ultimate echo.
魅了されていく
I'm becoming fascinated.
忘れないでね
Please don't forget
私の声を
my voice.
画面越しでも
Even through a screen,
ちゃんと愛して
love me properly.
ヴァーチャルだなんて突き放さないで
Don't just brush me off as 'virtual'.
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてね
Please remember
私の声を
my voice.
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
This whole body you gave me.
見つめあう
We gaze at each other,
あなたと二人重ねて
layered together.
息と音をヒビカセ
Let our breaths and sounds resonate.
あなたの初音
Your 'first sound',
この声聴かせ
let me hear this voice.
音 ヒビカセ
Let the sound resonate.
はい！
Yes!
というわけでみなさん！
Alright then, everyone!
新衣装になりました！
I'm in my new outfit!
どうですか？
What do you think?
か、かっこいいですか？
I-Is it cool?
なんと今回はダンスを頑張ると決めた
I decided I'd do my best at dancing this time,
その時から決めていた、ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装になってみました。
and I decided back then to go with this cool-looking dance outfit.
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんな写真いっぱい撮って
Everyone, take lots of pictures!
撮って、撮って、撮って！
Take pictures, take pictures, take pictures!
イェーイ！かっこいいでしょ？
Yay! Isn't it cool?
ちょっとかわいいばっかなんだけど
I'm always just so cute, but...
かっこいいはどこいったんだよ
Where'd the "cool" go?
おい！かっこいいはどこいったんだよ！
Hey! Where'd the cool go?!
じゃあ、というわけで新衣装になりました。
So yes, I'm in my new outfit.
ゲストパートのね、絶対アイドル辞めないでから
From the guest part, "Zettai Idol Yamenai de!",
あのソロになりましてUNDED響かせてと続けてお送りさせていただきました。
we moved on to my solo, "UNDED Hibikasete".
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ、めっちゃ頑張って、あの、足ちぎれそうってそういうことです。
I tried so hard. When I say my legs feel like they're tearing off,
本当にたくさん今回は変身のために飛びました。
I really jumped around a lot this time to transform.
足がちぎれそうです。
My legs feel like they're tearing off.
絶対アイドル辞めないでもね、先輩方、そらとも、ラプどの、来てくれてありがとう！
For "Zettai Idol Yamenai de!", my senpai, Soratomo-senpai and Lap-dono came out. Thank you!
げきむずだったね！ほんとに！
That was super hard, wasn't it?! Seriously!
本当に激ムズでしたね。
It really was super hard!
皆さん、一緒に頑張ってくださり、本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you all so much for working hard with me.
そ、そしてですね、あの、この後もまだまだゲストさんたくさん読んでおります。
And also, I still have many more guests joining me after this.
そしてござるも実はこのこのカラーリングだけじゃ実は無いんですよ。
And actually, Gozaru... This isn't the only color scheme!
なのでそちらも公開していくので、皆の衆お楽しみに！
So, I'll be revealing that too, so please look forward to it!
それでは、次はゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます。
Well then, next up, I'll be singing with my guest!
それでは、どうぞー！
And now, please welcome them!
ブラックロックシューター どこへ行ったの？
Black Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
作詞・作曲：ryo (supercell)
Lyrics & Music: ryo (supercell)
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much longer do I have to shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much longer do I have to cry?
もうやめて 私もう走れない
Please stop, I can't run anymore
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing
真っ暗で明かりもない
It's dark and there's no light to be seen
崩れかけたこの道で
On this crumbling path
あるはずのないあの時の希望が
The hope of that time, which shouldn't have existed,
見えた気がした
I felt as though I could see it.
どうして
Why...
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
懐かしい記憶
Those nostalgic memories
ただ楽しかった
It was just so fun
あの頃を
back in those days.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
でも動けないよ
But I can't move.
闇を駆ける星に
To the star streaking through the darkness,
願いを
I make a wish.
もう一度だけ
Just one more time,
走るから
I'll run.
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
Scared, with a trembling voice, I whisper,
私の名前を呼んで
“Call out my name.”
夜明けを抱く空
The sky that holds the dawn,
境界線までの距離
the distance to the boundary line,
あともう一歩届かない
just one more step, and I can't reach.
こらえた涙が溢れそうなの
The tears I held back are about to overflow.
今下を向かないで
Don't look down now,
止まってしまう
or you will stop.
未来を生きていたいんだ
I want to live in the future.
わかったの
I understand now.
思い出して強く
Remembering, strongly,
強く信じるの
strongly, I believe.
そうよ
That's right.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
優しい匂い
A gentle scent.
痛いよ 辛いよ
It hurts, it's painful,
飲み込む言葉
the words I swallow.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
動くこの足
These feet are moving.
世界を
The world...
超えて
I'll go beyond it.
最初からわかっていた
I've known from the very beginning
ここにいることを
that I am here.
私の中の
Inside of me,
全ての勇気が
all the courage
火を灯して
lights a fire.
もう逃げないよ
I won't run away anymore.
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
ひとりじゃないよ
I'm not alone.
声をあげて泣いたって
Even if I shout and cry,
構わない
it doesn't matter
ブラック★ロックシューター
BLACK★ROCK SHOOTER
見ていてくれる
You're watching over me
今から始まるの
It's starting now
私の物語
My story
忘れそうになったこの歌を
This song I almost forgot
歌うの
I'll sing it
息詰まるばかりって
Just feeling suffocated
俯いたこの道の先で
at the end of this road, looking down
ルールは無視で
I wanna ignore the rules
生きたいね ha ha
and live my life, ha ha
So pump up, pump up, ha
Beyond the way
作詞:q*Left 作曲:Giga
Lyrics: q*Left / Music: Giga
悟られそうね
They might find out
科学的じゃない
It's not scientific
もう聞き飽きた
I'm tired of hearing it
You talk too much like that
じゃあ言わないかい？
Then won't you say it?
しょうもない
It's worthless
Yeah 無理めな question
Yeah, an impossible question
裸足の fiction
Barefoot fiction
You make me sick and なんなんで
You make me sick, and why?
I know the way
寝返ってる間に叶わない
It won't come true while you sleep
無理やり twenty-four 変わらない
Forcing it 24/7 won't change a thing
暗い 暗い
Dark, dark
覚醒 find the way
Awaken, find the way
待って light on up
Wait, light on up
色々考えない
don't think too much
やっと違いですら
I'm even tired of hearing
もう聞き飽きたわ
about our differences
それは誰かのところまで
That's up to someone else
take me higher
どっちつかずじゃ No no no no
Being indecisive, no no no no
無理って言って超えようTry！
Say "impossible" and overcome it, try!
でしょう
Right?
悟られそうね
They might find out
科学的じゃない
It's not scientific
もうずっとちゃんとしないのは
Not doing things properly
それは誰のせい
Whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を描こう
Let's draw an endless dream
願ったまま 欲しがった
Just as I wished, I wanted it
それはTalking head
That's a talking head
終わらない夜を
Let's get through
越えていこう
the endless night
心のまんま
With all my heart
焦がれた向こう側へ
to the other side I longed for
羽ばたき消せない
I can't erase the flapping
操作なんてもういっちゃえ
Just say "screw this"
とか運命感じる感受性
A sensitivity that feels like fate
負けない
I won't lose
頂へ
To the top
吠えろ
Roar!
いつも number one
Always number one
そこどけ そこどけ
Move it, move it
運命
Destiny
I can see the light
扉の向こう
Beyond the door
Yeah, Yeah!
Shake it, まだまだ
Shake it, not yet!
Go beyond the way!
息詰まるばかりって
Just feeling suffocated
紡いだ言葉を探して
Searching for the words we've spun
歩み 研ぎ澄ませ
Sharpening my senses as I walk
本能に従って行け
Follow your instincts and go
Far from where the mirror
Follow me follow me heart
思うまま夢を描こう
Let's draw our dreams as we please
描いて
Let's draw them
願いのまま星が舞った
The stars danced just as I wished
終わらない夜を越えていこう
Let's get through this endless night
越えていこう
Let's get through it
このまま光の向こう側へ
Just like this, to the other side of the light
追いかけて合わせて
Chasing and matching up
出した姿作った
Creating the form I showed
もう一生何もやめない
I won't stop anything for my whole life
光の向こう側へ
To the other side of the light
Already started
You'll go beyond the way
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、本日はこのお二人に
And so, today we have these two
来ていただきましたー！
with us!
わーい！
Yay!
Yaaaay! It's me!
イマちゃん、ありがとう！
Thank you, Ima-chan!
アイアイアイアイアイ！
Ai ai ai ai ai!
せーの、お誕生日おめでとう！
Ready, set, Happy Birthday!
やったーありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
ね、お忙しいのにお二人とも、今日はね
You're both so busy, but you came today.
てかもうずっとレッスンからか
Well, you've been with me since the lessons.
本当にお付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for joining me.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you for having us.
今回はですね、誕生日で実は衣装が…
So this time, for my birthday, I actually got an outfit...
衣装が…
...an outfit...
ストッキング可愛い
The stockings are cute!
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
見てみて！いや、めっちゃ可愛い！
Look! Wow, so cute!
おへそ、おへそ見えちょる！
Your belly button, I can see it!
へそ、やべ、取られる。
My belly button, oh no, it'll be stolen.
後ろ可愛いよ、めっちゃ。
The back is super cute too.
ね、可愛い！
Yeah, it's cute!
本当は…めっちゃめっちゃ可愛い！
Actually... Super super cute!
似合ってる、めっちゃ似合ってる。
It suits you, it really suits you.
そうなんです。新しくね、ダンスする用みたいなね、衣装になったので
That's right. I got a new outfit that's like, for dancing.
これは…恐れ多くも二人を呼ぼうかな
So... I was wondering if I could be so bold as to invite you two.
ダンスが上手いお二人を呼んでいいかなって言って呼ばせていただきました。
The two of you who are great at dancing, so I invited you.
ええー！ / え、え、え？
Whaaat!? / W-w-what?
あなた、あなた方。
You, you two.
あなた方。
Us two.
いや、めっちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
Man, that was so much fun!
楽しかったー！
It was fun!
いや、レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして
Yeah, for the lessons too, you worked so hard with me,
でも二人ともめちゃくちゃ元がうまいから
But you two are so good to begin with,
風真一人だけ「どうしようかな、これ」
so I was thinking, "What should I do..."
「二人呼んで大丈夫だったかな」
"Was it okay to invite them?"
上手だった。めっちゃ上手だったよ。
You were great. You were really great.
めっちゃ踊った！
We danced a lot!
最高のものができたと思います。
I think we created something amazing.
みんな、いいものできたよねって、今頃コメントには
Everyone, "we made something great," I bet the comments
めっちゃ良かったよーが流れてると思います。
are full of "That was amazing!"
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい。
That makes me so happy.
だって、Uyuちゃんとは初めてじゃん、一緒にダンスするの。
Because, this is the first time dancing with Uyu-chan, right?
ま、こういう、こういうダンス初めて。
Well, this kind of dance is a first.
うーん、名将だし。
It's an honorable title.
めっちゃくちゃ嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
いや、嬉しい。
Yeah, I'm happy.
いや、ほんと誘ってよかった。
I'm so glad I invited you.
えーよかった！嬉しい！
Yay, that's great! I'm so happy!
いや、２人と一緒にね、このね、期間一緒に踊って、
Dancing with you two during this period...
めっちゃくちゃ勉強になりました先生方。
...was a huge learning experience, teachers.
そんなことないですよ。
No, it's nothing like that.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much.
いや、もう本当に。え、またね、何かあったらぜひ一緒に踊って。
Yeah, really. If there's another chance, please let's dance together.
やったー！
Yay!
一緒にやりましょう！
Let's do it together!
やりましょう。いつでも呼んでください。
Let's do it. Invite me anytime.
ぜひやりましょう。
Let's definitely do it.
じゃあ、ちょっとこの記念に、
Okay, to commemorate this...
この友情の証、
as proof of our friendship,
強い、かっこいいポーズ、写真撮っとこ。
let's strike a strong, cool pose for a picture.
かっこいいポーズ？かっこいいポーズ。
A cool pose? A cool pose.
ふう。
Whew.
かっこいいポーズを思いつかない。
I can't think of a cool pose.
なんだ？
What is it?
かわいいや。
It's cute.
かわいい。めっちゃかわいい。
Cute. So cute.
ま、いっか。
Oh well, whatever.
みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してくださいね。
Everyone, please post a lot on social media.
かしゃ。
Got it.
はい。
Yes.
と、言いつつ、実はですね、もう一つお願いがあって。
While we're at it, I actually have one more request.
おお？
Oh?
今日この後、今日初お披露目のオリ曲があって。
After this, today, I have a new original song to premiere.
オリ曲！
Original song!
おおお！やった！
Ohhh! Yay!
とうとう！
Finally!
楽しみ！
I'm so excited!
そうなんすよ。
That's right.
楽しみ！楽しみだ！
I'm excited! I'm so excited!
どんな曲？
What kind of song?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて。
After all, I, Kazama Iroha, want to be cool.
今回はかっこいい曲を持ってまいりました！
So this time, I've brought a cool song!
わあ！楽しみ！
Wow! I'm so excited!
It's cool. Yeah!
可愛くてかっこいいお二人から、やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから
I thought I'd get some courage from you two, who are cute and cool.
かっこいいビーム？
A cool beam?
え、待って、もらおう。かっこいいビーム、ふぁー！
Wait, let me have it. Cool beam, fwaaah!
あ、すごい。なんか、すごく、なんか、ちょっとイケメンになってきてる気がする。
Whoa, amazing. I feel like I'm becoming a little handsome.
ちょっとイケメンのポーズ分かんない。こう。
I don't know a handsome pose. Like this?
いいよ、かっこいいじゃん！
Nice, that's cool!
え、イケてる気がする。
Yeah, I feel like I look cool.
イケてる！
You look cool!
イケてる！行けちゃう、行けちゃう。
You look cool! I can do it!
よし。二人からめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたんで、頑張ってきますでござる。
Alright. I got a ton of energy from you two, so I'll go do my best.
頑張って！楽しみ！
Do your best! I'm excited!
お二人とも今日は本当に、お祝いと、そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて、そしてこの応援ビームをありがとうございました。
Thank you both for the celebration, for singing and dancing with me, and for that support beam.
こちらこそ、ありがとうございます！
Thank you too!
また遊びましょうね。
Let's hang out again.
はい。じゃあそれではこの後、新オリ曲を初お披露目させていただきます。
Yes. Well then, after this, I'll be premiering my new original song.
それでは、
And now,
せーの、どうぞー！
Ready, set, go!
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just from my appearance
ワタシのこと可愛いだけと
That I'm just a cute girl
まさか思っていないよね？
Surely you don't think that, do you?
ワタシの真実(ホント)
The real me
知っていてほしい
I want you to know
ホントノワタシ
The real me
Passion Passion Burning Emotion
Passion, passion, burning emotion
予測誤差の範囲と
The range of prediction errors
不測の事態も動じない
and unexpected situations don't faze me.
おすましフェイスでいるけど
I put on a prim and proper face, but
心は常に青白く燃える
my heart is always burning pale blue.
諦めはしない
I won't give up,
媚びたりもしない
I won't try to flatter,
ワタシを曲げない
I won't bend who I am.
扱いやすいヤツだと思うな
Don't think I'm easy to handle.
あまく見ると痛い目みるぞ
If you underestimate me, you'll get hurt.
それでもときには
But even so, sometimes,
逃げ出してしまいたい
I just want to run away.
そんな衝動に
Driven by that impulse,
弱音吐きたくなる真夜中もある
there are nights I want to complain.
ほんの小さな小さな妥協が
A tiny little compromise
積み重なり重なって動けない
piles up until I can't move.
大きな大きな可能性なくし
I lose my great potential
未来を狭めてしまうから
and narrow my own future.
どんなに暗くても辛くても後悔だけはしない
No matter how dark or painful, I won't have regrets.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて
Being cool isn't about looks,
生きかたなんだ
it's how you live your life.
現実と理想との
The distance between reality and my ideals,
距離を縮められたとしても
even if I could close it...
おすましフェイスでいるだけ
Just putting on a prim face,
何事もなかったかのように
as if nothing ever happened.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stop.
後戻りもない
There's no turning back.
夢を捨てない
I won't abandon my dream.
らしいとからしくないとか
'Like me' or 'not like me'
決めつけないで全部がワタシ
Don't define me, all of it is me.
それでもときには
But even so, sometimes,
温もりが恋しい
I long for warmth.
そんな感情に
By such feelings,
流されてしまいそうな真夜中もある
there are nights I feel swept away.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ
Only these sweet, sweet things...
求めてしまうような弱さいらない
I don't need a weakness that seeks them.
苦い苦い経験だって
Even bitter, bitter experiences
ワタシを強くしてくれるから
will make me stronger.
これが これが ワタシの
This is, this is my...
真実（ホント）
...truth (the real me).
とても狭い狭い世界の
In a very small, narrow world,
中だけで終わらせたくはないんだ
I don't want to end it all.
広い広い世界の果てまで
To the ends of this wide, wide world,
駆けぬけて生きてくんだから
I'll run on and live my life.
どんなに険しくて過酷でも楽しんでやるさ
No matter how steep or harsh, I'll enjoy it all.
イケてるのは
What's cool...
見た目じゃなくて
It's not about how you look,
生きかたなんだから
it's about how you live.
はい。というわけで皆さん
Yes. And so, everyone,
ゲストパートから続けて新オリ曲
continuing from the guest part, my new original song,
「ホントノワタシ」歌って踊らせていただきました！
“The Real Me”, I sang and danced for you!
なんと風真いろは7曲目のオリ曲です！
Believe it or not, this is my 7th original song!
ちょっとオリ曲のジャケットも届いているので
I've also received the jacket art for the song,
見ていきましょう。こちらです！
so let's take a look. Here it is!
はい。
Yes.
こちらの風真いろは新オリ曲7曲目
This is my 7th new original song,
ホントの…あ、ホントノワタシは
“Honto no…”, oh, “Honto no Watashi” is...
こちら日付変わりまして19日0時よりリリースされることとなりました。
It will be released at midnight on the 19th!
今回の新衣装にちなんでこちら作っていただきました。
I had this made to match my new outfit.
はい。ちょっと今までとだいぶ
Yes. It's quite different
系統の違う曲になるんですけれども
from the style of songs I've done before.
あのいつもみんなねありがたいことに
You know, thankfully, everyone always
風真いろはのことかっこいいっていうよりもかわいいって
says that I, Kazama Iroha, am more cute than cool,
言ってくださる方がいっぱいいるので
and there are many who say that.
いやかっこいいとこもあるんだよっていうのを伝えたくて
But I wanted to show that I have a cool side too,
作らせていただきました。
so I had this song made.
こちらぜひ0時にリリースされたら
When it's released at midnight,
たくさん聞いてまた
please listen to it a lot, and also,
ハッシュタグ #みてみていろは殿で
with the hashtag #MiteMiteIrohadono,
感想とか教えていただいたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you shared your thoughts.
そしてそしてゲストパートについても
And also, regarding the guest part,
お話していきますかね。じゃあ戻って。
I should talk about that. Let's go back.
はい。ゲストでねミオ先輩と
Yes. For my guests, Mio-senpai,
そしてはじめちゃんベー先輩と
and then Hajime-chan and Bae-senpai
一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました。
sang and danced with me.
ミオ先輩そしてベーね
Mio-senpai, and Bae,
そしてはじめちゃん来てくれて
and Hajime-chan, for coming,
ありが、ありがとう！
thank you, thank you so much!
もう本当に歌も難しかったし
The song was really difficult, and...
ベーとはじめちゃんのやつに関しては
For Bae and Hajime-chan's part,
もうこれができなさすぎて
I was so bad at this one move,
一生やりすぎてあの、一生腰痛を抱えて
I practiced it forever and had a constant backache.
これ、これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。
This was the main cause of my muscle soreness.
はい。でもすごい一緒に歌って踊らせていただきまして
Yes. But getting to sing and dance together with them,
とってもとっても良い経験になりました。
was a really, really great experience.
皆さんありがとうございました。
Thank you, everyone.
さあというわけで
Well then,
次の曲に行く前に
before we go to the next song,
お水飲んでいいですか？
may I have some water?
お水飲みます。お水。
I'm going to have some water. Water.
ロゴも見て。実は変わってた。よし。
Look at the logo, too. It actually changed. Okay.
お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting.
息整えて
Okay, I've caught my breath.
はい。次の曲なんですけれども
Yes. For the next song,
やっぱりみんなバラードも好きだよって言ってくれる方が
a lot of you have told me you also like my ballads,
多いので今回の
so this time...
生誕ライブ、バラードやろうと思って持ってきました。
For my birthday live, I thought I'd perform a ballad.
はい。ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか色々練習したんですけど、
Yes. I practiced a lot to see if I could sing it coolly.
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので
I'll be singing it with all my heart,
聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you listen.
それでは、次の曲、お聴きください。
Well then, please listen to the next song.
W/X/Y
作詞・作曲 : Tani Yuuki
Lyrics/Composition: Tani Yuuki
W/X/Y
作詞・作曲 : Tani Yuuki
Lyrics/Composition: Tani Yuuki
垂れ流したテレビの音
The sound of the TV left on
溜めてしまった洗濯物は今日こそ
The laundry I let pile up, I'll do it today for sure
晴れでも会えて外には出ないでいよう
Even if it's sunny, let's meet but stay inside
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's toast with plain snacks and alcohol
2人 酸いも甘いも噛み合わないとしても
Even if the two of us don't quite click
お互い寄り添うように 少しずらしてみようよ
Let's try to adjust and get a little closer
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないよう
The sun you gave me, so it's not hidden by the moon
輝き絶えぬように 歌うメロディ
A melody I sing so its light never fades
戯れる Slowly flowing day
A playful, Slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going beyond just 'I love you'
似た者同士こうして 年老いるまで
Like two peas in a pod, until we grow old
笑っていたいね
I want to be laughing
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, Fall asleep in bed
起こすから morning callで
I'll wake you with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの足跡辿ると
Following the trail of clothes left behind
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
I'll take you by surprise and hug you from behind
つい、繰り返すと 忘れてしまいそうになるよ
If we keep doing this, I might start to forget
振り返ると 日々が当たり前じゃないこと
Looking back, that these days aren't a given
2人対の細胞 絡み合う特別を
The two of us, a pair of cells, this special bond
噛み締めて生きたいと思った
I want to cherish it as I live
まどろみ抱く正午
Embracing slumber at noon
吐息漏れた体温 微塵も逃さないよう
Your warm breath, I won't let a single speck escape
頭の中に刻む 甘いメモリー
Engraving this sweet memory in my mind
戯れる Slowly, flowing day
A playful, Slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going beyond just 'I love you'
違う者同士こうして 年老いるまで
Different as we are, let's be like this 'til we're old
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
Until we grow old, I wanna keep laughing
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, I fall asleep in bed
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手はね離さないでいて
Don't let go of our held hands
ごめん、これそばに居たいだけだね
Sorry, I just want to be by your side
抱えた想いは お互い様でしょ
The feelings we carry are mutual, aren't they?
ほら、あいこでしょ
We're quits, aren't we?
すれ違い、間違いもあるし
There are passing moments and mistakes
筋書き通り行かない
And things don't go according to plan
悲しみだって半分こにしよう
Let's share our sorrows in half
別れじゃない希望
It's not a farewell, it's hope
独りよがりにならないように、いつも
so it doesn't become selfish, always
君がいなきゃ 今もどこかで
Without you, even now, somewhere
動けないままの僕で
I'd be stuck, unable to move
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
I want to say thank you
これからは僕が支えてくって
From now on, I'll support you
呆れてしまうくらいにね
so much that you'll be amazed
愛が増していく day by day
My love grows day by day
面と向かうとどうしても
When we face each other, somehow
素直になれないな、ごめんね
I can't be honest, I'm sorry
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Playing around, a slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Going beyond just "I love you"
似た者同士 こうして
We're so alike, just like this
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
Until we grow old, I wanna keep laughing
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, I fall asleep in bed
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
はい、それではですね、
Right, well then,
皆さん、ここまで聞いていただきまして、本当にありがとうございます。
everyone, thank you so much for listening.
こんなに…ちょっと歌わせていただいたんですけども、
I got to sing for you just now,
バラード、なかなか3Dライブでやらないので、すごく緊張しました。
but since I don't often sing ballads in 3D lives, I was super nervous.
どうだったでしょうか？
How was it?
わ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ拍手と「めっちゃいい」っていうやつが見える。ありがとうございます。
Whoa, I can see lots of applause and "That was great!" comments. Thank you.
そして、ここで皆さんお待ちかねの、あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います。
And now, I'd like to make the announcement you've all been waiting for.
それでは、元気に行きます。
Alright, let's get right to it!
それでは、ドン！
Here we go, boom!
風真いろは 2025誕生日記念グッズ
Kazama Iroha's 2025 Birthday Celebration Merch!
出まーす！
It's time!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ビジュアルが大変よろし！
The visuals are so great!
こちらのグッズが販売決定です！
The sale of these goods has been decided!
はい！というわけで詳細を見ていきましょう。どん！
Yes! So, let's look at the details. Boom!
回転アクリルスタンド
Revolving Acrylic Stand
はい、まず1つ目は回転アクリルスタンド。
Yes, first up is the Revolving Acrylic Stand.
え、イラストはNardack先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei.
うわー！
Wow!
こちらですね、あの、こういうことです。
This one is, um... like this.
あの、裏表になってるって言いたい。
I mean, it's double-sided.
裏、裏表になってる。
It's front and back.
そう、カラーライズ衣装とこの新しい新衣装で
Yes, it's double-sided with the Color-Rise outfit
裏表になってます。くるくる回せるので、
and this new outfit. You can spin it,
あの、ござるのこと回して遊んでください。
so please spin me around and have fun with it.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
そして次がこちら。
And next up is this.
温感湯呑
Heat-sensitive Teacup
はい、温感湯呑み。
Yes, a heat-sensitive teacup.
これついさっきサンプルが控室に届いて試しました。
A sample arrived in the waiting room and I tried it.
あの、ちゃんとあったかいの入れるとふわーってですね、
If you put something hot in it, Pokobee appears.
ちゃんとポコべーが出て、ござるが打ち合わせとかね、
And it properly turned back green after cooling down.
こちらもすごく可愛くて、
This is also super cute.
お寿司屋さんとかにあるサイズなのかな？結構大きめの
It's a proper, rather large teacup.
ちゃんといた湯呑みです。ぜひね、使ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you used it!
はい、そして次がこちら。
Yes, and next up is this.
いろはぬいぐるみ ポップダンス衣装ver.
Iroha Plushie Pop Dance Outfit ver.
はい、風真いろは、新、こちらポップダンス衣装って
Yes, Kazama Iroha's new pop dance outfit plushie!
名前なんですけど、のぬいぐるみです。
I really want you to get one.
ぜひお迎えしてほしいな。ござるさんのぬいぐるみで
Everyone, please play with Gozaru's plushie!
みんな遊んでくれ！っていうことで、このツインテールのね、新衣装、
So, this twintail new outfit has become a plushie!
なんとぬいぐるみになりました。あの、手持ちじゃなくて、
I'd be so happy if you displayed it in your home.
こ、こういうタイプだったかな？だと思うので、
And next is this.
おそろいネックレス
Matching Necklace
はい、なんとござるのこれ、これとおそろいのこれが出ます！
Yes, this! It's a necklace that matches mine!
ちょ、ちょっと待ってね。もっかい言い直していい？
Wait, let me say that again. A necklace that matches this!
はい。
Yes.
で、普段ね、アクセサリーとか着けないたいしさんね、
For those who don't usually wear accessories,
着けないよっていう方も、ま、よかったらこちらね、あの、
you could attach it to the plushie as a set,
さっきのぬいぐるみにあの、くくって一緒にセットに
or I'd be happy if you wore it to events.
飾っていただいたりとか、イベントの時に着けてきてくれたら
It's stylish. Let's match, if you'd like!
嬉しいです。おしゃれです。ござると一緒に、お揃いに、
So, the full set looks like this!
よかったらし、しましょう。というわけで、
Wow!
そしてフルセットがこんな感じ？うわー、
It looks so refreshing, doesn't it?
なんだか爽やかですね。そう、ライブタイトルの通り
Like the title, it's reversible, so there are various
リバーシブルなんで、色々ちょっと、反転反転が付いてたり
inverted things. And the purchase bonus is this.
します。そして購入特典はこちら。
Full Set Purchase Bonus
この戦争を終わらせに来ました。
I've come to end this war.
今回はですね、グッズが2種類出るということで、数量限定は
Since there are two sets, I made a special bonus.
せずに、ちょっと変わった特典にしてみました。こちらは
It comes with a double-sided tarot card.
裏表のタロットカードが付いてきます。片面にはね、
One side has my printed signature and a message.
風真の、えっと、複製サインとメッセージが入っております。
This one is also double-sided...
楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could enjoy it.
数量限定とかではないので
It's not limited edition,
ゆっくりね、あの購入していただければと思います。
so feel free to take your time purchasing it.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど、
Sales start after this at 9 PM,
ちょっと生配信の関係上、
but due to the livestream,
ちょっと生配信伸びる可能性のが今大なので
there's a high chance it will be extended.
生配信中に皆さん、
Everyone, during the livestream,
あの、カト見に行ってください。
please go check out the cart.
あ、でも、あの数量限定とかないので
Oh, but it's not a limited quantity item,
安心してください。
so please rest assured.
はい。そしてフルセットの特典もう一つあります。
Yes. And there's one more bonus for the full set.
こちらです。
Here it is.
はい。みんな大好き
Yes. Everyone's favorite,
ホロかのカードが1枚ついてきます。
a hololive Official Card Game card is included.
はい、皆さんよかったらお手にとって
Yes, everyone, if you'd like, please get it.
ホロカ勢の皆さんは使ってくださいね。
And for all you Holo-ca players, please use it.
遊び方とかあとカードの詳細は
For how to play and card details,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの
please check the official homepage
公式ホームページにてご確認ください。
for the hololive Official Card Game.
よし、今台本めっちゃ見た。
Okay, I just peeked at the script.
言えなかったらやばいと思って。
I thought it'd be bad if I couldn't say it.
そしてこちら、一緒に入れさせていただくカードは
And the included card
日本語版のみとなっておりますので、
is only available in the Japanese version,
ご了承ください。
so please be aware of that.
はい。カートのオープンですが、
Yes. As for the shop opening,
こちらですね、100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ、
it's for both the 1M subscriber and birthday goods
両方同時なので皆さんよろしくお願いします。
at the same time, so please check it out.
ちょっとごめんなさい、生配信押しちゃってごめんね。
Sorry for the stream running late.
ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信を
To the other Holomem streaming,
してすみません。
I'm sorry for streaming at the same time.
はい。というわけで、ちょっとお水飲みます。
Okay. With that, I'll have some water.
わけです。
That's how it is.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、あと最後の、お知らせとしまして、
So, for the last announcement...
この後、本編終了次第
After this main part ends,
ちょっとまた時間がね、確定したら15分からか20分からか
it'll be in about 15 or 20 minutes,
どっちかになると思うんですけど、
though we'll confirm the time.
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定の
There will be a members-only encore live
アンコールライブもございますので、
for Kazama Iroha.
皆が見たかったあの曲やこの曲を
I'll sing and dance to the songs
歌ったり踊ったりしますので、
that everyone wanted to see.
よかったら見に来てください。
So please come and watch if you'd like.
よろしくお願いします。
Please do.
メンバーシップギフトとか今日から入ってくださった隊士さんも
Thanks to the Taishi who joined with gifts today!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you!
はい。
Yes.
そしてなんと残念なことに、
And now, unfortunately,
次の曲が皆さん、
the next song...
このライブ最後の曲となります。
will be the last song of this live.
ええ、皆さん、もう最後は何を歌うか
Well, everyone, I think many of you
ある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが
have already guessed what the last song will be.
改めまして、この度は
Once again, for coming to
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025,
お越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございます。
thank you so much.
そして、あの、制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださった
And to the staff who worked so hard,
スタッフさんやダンスの先生やマネージャーさんや、
the dance teacher, my manager,
皆さん、本当に、クリエイターの皆さんも
to all the creators, everyone,
ありがとうございました。
thank you so much.
あの、正直、色々あった
Honestly, after everything that happened
昨年の年末から、
since the end of last year,
ここまで声が戻って
for my voice to recover this much
ライブができるっていうことがほぼ奇跡、
and do a live is almost a miracle.
なんだったらもう半分諦めかけていた
If anything, I had half given up.
いたんですけども、スタッフの皆さんや
I was... and the staff...
ファンの隊士さんたちがすごい支えてくださって、
and my fans, the Taishi, have been so supportive.
いろんな方に支えられて本日、
With the support of so many people, today
実施することができました。
I was able to hold this event.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so, so much.
正直、まだまだ本調子じゃない部分が多いのは
To be honest, there are still a lot of parts
正直なところです。
where I'm not at my best. That's the truth.
だけど今日、少しでもこのライブを見て、
But today, by watching this live show, even just a little,
たくさんの人に元気が一人でも多く
I hope that I was able to bring energy
届いていればなと思っております。
to as many people as possible.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、精一杯頑張って参りますので、
I'll continue with my rehabilitation and do my very best,
皆さん、これからもよろしくお願いします。
so everyone, I look forward to your continued support.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲、
And so, a fitting song for the finale...
皆さん最後に聞いてください。
Everyone, please listen to this last song.
風真いろは、新オリ曲、
Kazama Iroha's new original song,
『君にしか読めない手紙』
'A Letter Only You Can Read.'
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write 'thank you,'
毎日になっちゃうくらい
I'd be writing it every single day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings, which are too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
君にしか読めない手紙
A Letter Only You Can Read
作詞：HoneyWorks 作曲・編曲：HoneyWorks , MARUMOCHI
Lyrics: HoneyWorks / Music & Arrangement: HoneyWorks, MARUMOCHI
La la la 拝啓
La la la, Dear...
私を形作った君へ
To you, who shaped me.
愛も変わらず言葉を届け続けています
I'm still sending you my words with unchanging love.
La la la 拝啓
La la la, Dear...
未来で私待ってる君へ
To you, who's waiting for me in the future.
響く音に憂いなどなくお過ごしでしょうか？
I hope you're living your days without sorrow.
不安が無い日なんて 多分無かったけど
There probably wasn't a day without anxiety, but...
私の言葉 君の言葉 重なって笑えたんだ
My words and your words overlapped, and I could smile.
ありがとう書くとしたら
If I were to write 'thank you,'
毎日になっちゃうくらい
I'd be writing it every single day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings, which are too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいるそれだけでさ理由になるなんて
Just the fact that you're here is reason enough,
奇跡
it's a miracle.
ありがとう足りないの誤魔化すよう
Saying 'thank you' feels like I'm hiding that it's not enough.
愛してる
I love you.
魔法石のブレスレット
A magic stone bracelet,
シロツメクサの女王様
the queen of the white clovers.
プラスチックだらけの宝石箱で
In a jewelry box full of plastic,
ずっと遊べるよ君と
I can play with you forever.
思い出の欠片たち 溢れるこの場所で
With fragments of memories overflowing in this place,
私の言葉 君の言葉 重ねて
My words and your words layered together,
笑ってた
we laughed.
重ねてたい 笑ってたい
I want to be together, I want to laugh
忘れられる 世界で今
In a world where we can forget,
私が選んだ 生き方
is the way of life I chose.
手紙をさ 書いたからさ
I wrote a letter, so
この音に 乗せて
I'll put it to this sound.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write "Thank you",
毎日になっちゃう くらい
it would take every single day.
重すぎる 私の想いは
These feelings of mine are too heavy,
最後に 伝えるね
so I'll tell you at the end.
君がいる それだけでさ
Just the fact that you're here,
理由になるなんて 奇跡
is a miracle of a reason.
ありがとう 足りないの
"Thank you" isn't enough.
誤魔化すよ
I'll fudge it and just say
愛してる
I love you.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
風真いろは
Kazama Iroha
100万人記念
1 Million Subscriber Celebration
7月1日
July 1st
MV公開
MV Release
君にしか読めない手紙
A Letter Only You Can Read
風真いろは 100万人記念
Kazama Iroha 1M Sub Celebration
「君にしか読めない手紙」
"A Letter Only You Can Read"
7月1日 MV公開
MV Release on July 1st
Reversible
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025